这里是纽约
This is New York.
而这就是纽约市的地铁
And this is the New York City subway.
轨道绵延六百英里
600 miles of track,
星罗棋布着四百余座车站
over 400 stations,
每日客流量超过三百万
and a daily ridership of more than 3 million people.
它是世界上最令人叹为观止的交通系统之一
It's one of the most impressive transit systems in the world.
但曾几何时，它的面貌可能截然不同
But once upon a time, it could have looked completely different.
有轨电车曾计划横贯整座城市
Trams crossing the entire city.
高架列车也曾在三十英尺的高空呼啸而过
Elevated trains 30 feet in the air.
甚至有计划将整个地铁规模扩大一倍
Plans to double the size of the entire subway,
线路从曼哈顿一直延伸到斯塔滕岛
with lines running from Manhattan to Staten Island.
这个故事讲述的，是那些几乎实现却又终未成真的城市交通规划
This is the story of the plans for the city's transit that almost but never quite happened.
在一场长达数十年的纽约地铁争夺战中
Stopped in their tracks, defeated in a decades-long battle
这些计划最终被击败，永远停在了轨道上
for the New York City subway.
十九世纪初
In the early 1800s,
最早的永久性公共交通工具是沿街边钢轨由马匹牵引的
the first permanent mass transit was pulled by horses along steel rails in the street.
但马车问题重重
But the horse cars had problems.
牲畜会疲惫
Animals got tired.
它们既不可靠，又无法成立工会
They were unreliable. They couldn't unionize.
即便如此，你还是得喂养它们
But somehow you still had to feed them.
这是一种过时的技术
They were an outdated technology.
城市亟需替代品
The city needed a replacement.
从1825年到1899年间
Between 1825 and 1899,
专利局总共收到了125份关于高架交通系统的方案
the patent office received a total of 125 plans for elevated transit systems.
第一个方案是拱廊铁路
The first plan was the arcade railway.
保留马匹，但将它们提升到街道上方的平台，而火车则在下方运行
Keep the horses, but elevate them to a platform above the street while trains ran below.
小约翰·兰德尔则提议，在百老汇沿线建造一条三英里长的高架轨道
John Randall Jr., a three-mile elevated track along Broadway.
詹姆斯·斯威特的构想是，用蒸汽机车悬吊着客车车厢
James Sweat, a steam-powered locomotive dangling passenger cars below.
还有鲁弗斯·吉尔伯特
There was also Rufus Gilbert,
他设计了一种由蒸汽气动装置驱动的高架列车
an elevated train powered by steam pneumatics
能将车厢从一站弹射到另一站
that launched cars from station to station.
几乎所有方案都是为百老汇大街设计的，那是全城最拥堵的街道
Almost all were for Broadway, the city's most congested street.
但问题随之而来
But there was a problem.
没人知道高架列车会提升还是拉低沿线的地价
No one knew whether an elevated train would raise property values or lower them.
因此，百老汇的店主们联手抵制任何可能影响他们地产价值的计划
So Broadway shopkeepers blocked any plan that could affect their property values.
只有一位政治大师，才能真正解决这拥堵的难题
Only a master politician could truly tackle the congestion.
查尔斯·哈维曾是一个成功项目的总工程师
Charles Harvey was the chief engineer on a successful project
该项目连接了苏必利尔湖和休伦湖
to link Lake Superior and Lake Huron.
这为他赢得了强大的政治盟友
That gave him powerful political allies.
哈维同样将高架交通视为解决纽约拥堵的良方
Harvey also saw elevated transit as the solution to New York's congestion.
但与其他发明家不同
But unlike the other inventors,
哈维选择远离百老汇那些难缠的地主
Harvey stayed away from the landowners on Broadway.
他计划在格林威治街和第九大道上建造一条高架铁路线
Instead, he wanted to build an elevated train line on Greenwich Street and 9th Avenue.
这个位置既能避开纷争，又足以发挥作用
Far enough away to avoid the conflict, but close enough to make a difference.
他自掏腰包，修建了一条试验轨道
With his own money, he built a test track.
如果计划失败，他会亲手拆除它
If his plan failed, he'd tear it down.
1867年，他驾驶着一节单车厢在半英里长的轨道上行驶
In 1867, he piloted a single car down a half-mile track,
最高时速达到了十英里
reaching a top speed of 10 miles per hour.
令人印象深刻
Impressive.
但它是靠缆绳牵引的
But it was pulled by a cable.
而缆绳总有断裂的风险
And cables break.
他还有足够的时间来改进
He had enough time to fix it.
但竞争者已悄然而至
But competitors were coming.
1863年，世界上第一条地下交通系统在伦敦开通后
In 1863, after the first underground transit system in the world opened in London,
阿尔弗雷德·伊莱·比奇坚信，解决交通拥堵的办法不在天上
Alfred Eli Beach was convinced the solution to traffic congestion wasn't above the street.
而是在地下
It was under it.
作为一名工程师，他的想法是利用巨大的蒸汽风扇产生的压缩空气
An engineer, his idea was to use compressed air propelled by a massive steam-powered fan
将车厢推过一个圆柱形管道
to push cars through a cylindrical tube.
但他必须秘密进行这项工程
But he had to build it in secret.
当时的纽约，被腐败的坦慕尼协会及其头目所控制
New York was under the grip of the corrupt Tammany Hall and its boss.
特威德老大
Boss Tweed.
威廉·马吉尔·特威德
他是一个利用政治权力为自己和同伙谋取私利的商人
A businessman who used his political power to enrich himself and his associates.
特威德与马车公司有着千丝万缕的联系
Tweed had deep ties to the horse car companies.
比奇曾试图获得建造地铁的官方许可
Beach tried to get official permission to build his subway.
但特威德处处阻挠
Boss Tweed blocked him at every turn.
于是他心生一计
So he hatched a plan.
他申请在百老汇地下建造一条气动邮件管道，而非地铁
Instead of a subway, he asked for permission to build a pneumatic mail tube under Broadway.
他租下了一栋百货公司的地盘
He leased a department store building.
并从那里开始挖掘隧道
And from there, he dug a tunnel.
隧道长三百一十二英尺，高八英尺
312 feet long and 8 feet high.
他采用了一种创新的隧道盾构法，以避免引起地面上的注意
He used an innovative tunneling shield method to avoid attracting attention at the surface.
一旦街道路面出现裂缝，计划便会满盘皆输
If the street pavement cracked, it was over.
他们只在夜间用手工工具劳作
They worked at night with hand tools.
所有材料都通过小巷运入建筑
Materials were carted into the building using side streets.
终于在1870年，他揭开了比奇气动交通项目的神秘面纱
And finally, in 1870, he revealed this beach pneumatic transit project.
一条功能齐全的地铁
A fully functional subway.
项目大获成功
It was a success.
于是比奇提议将其再延长五英里，直达中央公园
So Beach proposed to extend it another 5 miles to Central Park.
但许可再次被驳回
The permit was blocked again.
特威德刚刚为自己的纽约铁路公司拿到了一份特许经营权
Tweed had just gotten a charter for his own New York railway company.
他计划在曼哈顿建造自己的高架列车
And he had plans to build his own elevated train in Manhattan.
一场地上与地下的对决就此展开
It was now underground versus overground.
比奇威胁到了他的垄断地位
Beach threatened his monopoly.
哈维亦是如此
But so did Harvey.
哈维在曼哈顿西区的铁路项目开始初具规模
Harvey's railroad on Manhattan's west side was starting to take off.
他解决了一些技术上的难题
He fixed some of the technical setbacks.
他的投资者们也将公司重组为纽约高架铁路公司
And his investors reorganized his company into the New York Elevated Railway Company.
线路放弃了缆绳，转而使用蒸汽机车
Instead of cables, the lines were switched to steam powered locomotives.
这个方案奏效了
And it worked.
特威德向州议会提交了一项法案，意图宣布哈维的铁路为公害
Boss Tweed went to the state legislature with a bill to declare Harvey's train a public nuisance.
并寻求许可将其拆除
Seeking permission to tear it down.
但哈维手中握有一张王牌
But Harvey had a card in his favor.
他强大的政治盟友
Powerful political allies.
在他们的鼎力相助下，他成功挫败了特威德的法案
With their help, he managed to defeat Tweed's bill.
同年，一位名叫托马斯·纳斯特的漫画家将特威德拉下马
In the same year, Tweed was brought down by a cartoonist named Thomas Nast.
这些漫画引发了调查
The cartoons prompted investigations
揭露了其多年来的贪污、贿赂、裙带关系和选举舞弊
that uncovered years of embezzlement, bribes, nepotism, and rigged elections.
他最终被判犯有一百零二项罪名，获刑十二年
He was convicted of 102 separate crimes and sentenced to 12 years in prison.
随着特威德的倒台
With Tweed out of the picture,
竞争变成了哈维的高架列车与比奇的地铁之间的较量
it was now a race between Harvey's elevated train and Beach's subway.
一场世纪之战
The fight of the century.
谁将赢得最终的胜利？
Who was going to win?
是地下铁，还是高架蒸汽机？
Underground subway or elevated steam engine?
金融危机爆发了
Financial crisis.
投资者们变得忧心忡忡
Investors were nervous.
哈维的第九大道高架线已经证明了高架交通的可行性
Harvey's 9th Avenue L train had already proven the concept of elevated transit.
而比奇的气动地铁在某种程度上仍是一场实验
Beach's pneumatic subway was still somewhat of an experiment.
投资者们停止了对它的支持
Investors stopped backing it.
到了十九世纪末
By the late 1800s,
高架列车击败了地铁，并即将改变这座城市的格局
the L trains defeated the subway and were going to transform the city.
私营铁路公司在曼哈顿修建了数条高架铁路线
Private rail companies built several elevated train lines in Manhattan
通往那些曾经只是农田的区域
to areas that were previously nothing more than farmland.
这使得人们可以住得更远，同时又能享受到城市的便利
It allowed people to live further away, but still benefit from the city.
短短五年间，数百个街区的高架轨道拔地而起
In only five years, hundreds of blocks of elevated track were built.
哈莱姆区，这个曾经遍布农场和乡村庄园的田园之地
Harlem, once a rural area with farms and country estates,
如今已是联排房屋林立
was filled with row houses.
在布朗克斯，第三大道高架线在短短二十年内带来了五倍的人口增长
In the Bronx, the 3rd Avenue L led to a five-fold population increase in only 20 years.
但高架列车并非完美无瑕
But the L trains weren't perfect.
它们是悬在空中的庞大蒸汽引擎
They were gigantic steam engines in the air.
喷吐着有毒的浓烟，遮蔽了阳光，而且噪音震耳欲聋
They pumped out toxic smoke, blocked out the sun, and were incredibly noisy.
轨道变成了无形的界线
The tracks turned into boundaries.
夜间在桥下行走变得危险，因为那里聚集着三教九流之辈
It was dangerous to walk under them at night because of the shady people who hung there.
前方小混混推销广告，请空降8:04
然而，当所有高架线路在1880年统一归于曼哈顿铁路公司旗下时
But by the time all elevated lines were united under the Manhattan Railway Company in 1880,
它们早已被乘客需求压得不堪重负
they were already overwhelmed by passenger demand
而人口仍在持续爆炸式增长
and the population continued to explode.
从1880年到1905年，人口几乎增长了三倍
It nearly tripled between 1880 and 1905.
到1910年，仅曼哈顿一地的人口就达到了二百三十万的顶峰
By 1910, Manhattan alone reached a peak population of 2.3 million people.
通勤铁路的需求猛增
Demand for commuter rail soared.
房地产开发商不再追求垂直增长
Instead of vertical growth,
而是希望通过廉价的公共交通实现横向扩张
real estate developers wanted horizontal expansion enabled by cheap mass transit.
这已经彻底改变了人们的生活方式
It was already a total revolution in how people lived,
但另一场革命即将来临
but another one was coming.
1882年
In 1882,
托马斯·爱迪生在曼哈顿下城开设了珍珠街发电站
Thomas Edison opened the Pearl Street Power Station in Lower Manhattan,
这是世界上最早的集中式电网之一
one of the first centralized electrical grids in the world.
布鲁克林在1890年迎来了第一辆有轨电车
Brooklyn got its first electric streetcar in 1890,
从公园环路开往康尼岛
running from Park Circle to Coney Island.
然后人们的目光投向了高架铁路线下，看到了那些马车
Then they looked under the elevated train lines and they saw the horse cars.
他们不禁感叹，你们怎么还在这里？
And they were like, what are you still doing here?
电车的速度是马车的两倍，更可靠，也更高效
The trolleys were twice as fast, more reliable, and more efficient.
马车线路网进行了电气化改造，并在全城范围内扩展
The web of horse car lines electrified and expanded across the city.
但虽然有轨电车适合短途交通
But while streetcars were good for local transit,
对于长距离来说，它们仍然太慢了
they were still too slow for long distances.
不过它们证明了电力轨道车辆的可行性
But they proved the viability of electric railway vehicles.
既然电车能行，火车也同样可以
And if they worked for trolleys, they could work for trains.
高架线路改造成了电力驱动
The L-lines were converted to electricity.
再也没有了有毒的浓烟
No more toxic smoke.
而没有了烟雾，将它们建在地下的理由，也变得愈发充分
But without smoke, suddenly, it was much easier to justify building them underground.
1898年，纽约的五个行政区合并
In 1898, New York's five boroughs consolidated.
纽约市的行政区域扩大到了原来的十三倍
New York City's administrative area increased to 13 times its size.
它一跃成为全球特大城市，世界第二大都会
It became a global megacity, the second largest in the world.
伦敦在1890年就拥有了电气化地下系统
London had an electric underground system by 1890.
巴黎则在1900年的万国博览会上揭幕了其地铁
Paris unveiled its metro at the 1900 Exposition.
而纽约，这个本应与巨头并驾齐驱的城市，却已然落后
New York, now supposedly up there with the big dogs, was behind.
一旦五个行政区归于一个市政府管辖
Once the five boroughs were brought under one city government,
建设一个一体化的区域交通网络便显得名正言顺
the construction of an integrated regional transit network was justified.
地铁于1900年动工，短短四年内
Construction on the subway began in 1900, and in just four years,
九英里长的轨道和二十八个车站便宣告完工
nine miles of track and 28 stops were completed.
曼哈顿主线由政府出资，但由跨区捷运公司（IRT）私营
The Manhattan Main Line was publicly funded, but privately operated by the Interboro Rapid Transit Company, or IRT.
它从市政厅一直延伸到哈莱姆区，票价仅需五美分
It ran from City Hall to Harlem, all for just five cents.
但即便是第一条线路尚未完工，人们已经开始呼吁扩建
But even before the first line was finished, people were demanding expansions.
地铁扩建的初步规划由快速交通铁路委员会负责
The initial planning for subway expansion was overseen by the Board of Rapid Transit Railroad Commissioners.
1902年，他们要求总工程师威廉·巴克莱·帕森斯
In 1902, they asked Chief Engineer William Barclay Parsons
制定一套全面而深远的快速交通系统
to develop a general and far-reaching system of rapid transit
能覆盖纽约市及其五个行政区
covering the whole city of New York and all its five boroughs.
他的愿景包括将线路延伸至布鲁克林、布朗克斯和皇后区
His vision included expansions into Brooklyn, the Bronx, and Queens.
在曼哈顿，他们计划在东侧修建多条线路
In Manhattan, they planned multiple lines on the east side.
当帕森斯在1906年公布他的计划时，第一条地铁线已经运力饱和
By the time Parsons published his plan in 1906, the first subway line was already at capacity.
到1908年，地铁日均客流量已达八十万人次
By 1908, the subway averaged 800,000 passengers a day.
快速交通委员会随之解散
The Rapid Transit Commission was dissolved.
从那时起，交通事务改由州公共服务委员会（PSC）监管
From then on, transit was overseen by the State Public Service Commission.
没人认为公共服务委员会能同时处理好地铁运营和所有其他公共事业
No one thought the PSC could juggle both subway operation and all other public utilities.
但公共服务委员会决心证明他们错了
But the PSC wanted to prove them wrong.
他们提出了三区计划，该计划包含三条主干线路
They came up with the Triborough Plan, which had three main routes.
它从曼哈顿的南端一直延伸到布朗克斯
It stretched from the tip of Manhattan to the Bronx.
一条地铁线在布鲁克林的第四大道下穿行
A subway that ran under 4th Avenue in Brooklyn.
线路还分支出去，通往湾脊、康尼岛和布鲁克林的其他社区
Lines branched off and ran to Bay Ridge, Coney Island, and other Brooklyn neighborhoods.
三区计划至关重要
The Triborough Plan was important.
其中大部分都已建成
Most of it was built.
但随后，扩建陷入了停滞
But then, expansion stagnated.
纽约市长与公共服务委员会之间存在着理念上的分歧
There were philosophical differences between New York's mayor and the PSC.
盖诺市长希望延伸现有线路
Mayor Gaynor wanted to extend existing lines.
而公共服务委员会则想要一个全新的独立系统
PSC wanted a new, independent system.
私营铁路公司也停滞不前
The private railroad companies stagnated.
由于缺乏政治方向和竞争
With no political direction and no competition,
跨区捷运公司和布鲁克林捷运公司都没有动力去扩展他们的地铁系统
the IRT and BRT had no incentive to expand their subway systems.
直到一位局外人，威廉·吉布斯
That was until an outsider, William Gibbs,
想要将三区路线与他自己的铁路系统连接起来
wanted to link the Triborough routes with his own railroad system.
面对新的竞争，IRT和BRT被迫再次开始扩张
With the new competition, the IRT and BRT were prompted to expand again.
他们签署了一份协议，即双重合同
They signed a deal, the dual contracts.
一份与IRT签订，一份与BRT签订，这引发了一波地铁扩建浪潮
One with the IRT and one with the BRT, which led to a wave of subway expansion.
市政府建造了新的地铁和新的高架线路，并对现有线路进行了改造
The city built new subways and new elevated lines, as well as rehabilitated existing lines.
然后将它们租给私营公司运营
Then they leased them to the private companies for operation.
成本由市政府和公司共同分担
Cost was shared between the city and companies.
在双重合同下的这一次扩张，就建成了今天使用的大部分地铁系统
The single expansion under the dual contracts built the majority of the subway system used today.
地铁扩建虽大获成功
Despite the successful expansion of the subway,
但在时人眼中，公共服务委员会依然机构臃肿，效率低下
the PSC was still seen as too cumbersome and slow.
它的任务还包括建设快速交通，以及监管市内所有其他公用事业公司
It was also tasked with the construction of rapid transit and regulating all other public utility corporations within the city.
因此在1919年，纽约州长阿尔弗雷德·E·史密斯主张，这些职能必须分开
So in 1919, Alfred E. Smith, the governor of New York, argued that these functions had to be separate.
他签署了法案，将公共交通的控制权从公共服务委员会手中夺回
He signed legislation to take control of public transit away from the PSC.
他的新交通建设专员任命了一位名叫丹尼尔·劳伦斯·特纳的男子为总工程师
His new transit construction commissioner appointed a man named Daniel Lawrence Turner as chief engineer.
特纳希望将城市人口分散到所有五个行政区
Turner wanted to spread out the city's population across all five boroughs.
1920年，他发布了他雄心勃勃的综合计划
In 1920, he released his ambitious, comprehensive plan.
超过八百三十英里的新路线
Over 830 miles of new routes.
比现有系统的里程数增加了一倍以上
More than double the system's existing mileage.
甚至比今天的规模还要大
And even more than what's there today.
所有工程计划在二十五年内建成
All built within 25 years.
但政治再次成为绊脚石
But then politics got in the way again.
市长约翰·F·海兰坚称，交通系统应由市政府拥有
The mayor, John F. Hyland, was adamant that the city should own the transit system.
而不是州政府，也不是私营公司
Not the state and not private companies.
他曾因在弯道上鲁莽驾驶火车而被BRT解雇
He was once fired from the BRT for driving a train at a reckless speed around a curve.
因此他对私营地铁公司怀恨在心
So he held a deep-seated grudge against the privately operated subway companies.
他想把IRT和BRT逼上绝路
He wanted to push the IRT and BRT out of business.
他扣留了新线路的资金，拒绝发放建筑许可，并拒绝提高五美分的票价
He withheld funds for new lines, denied building permits, and refused to raise the five-cent fare.
希望以此切断他们的收入来源
Hoping to cut off their revenue.
他摧毁私营铁路公司的宏伟计划
His master plan to destroy the private rail companies
是通过公共地铁扩建来直接与它们竞争
was a public subway expansion designed to directly outcompete them.
这个计划雄心勃勃
It was ambitious.
他将建造超过一百英里的新线路，并从私营公司手中接管另外一百英里
He would build over a hundred miles of new lines and take over another hundred from private companies.
所有工程计划在三年内完成
All completed within three years.
但他有一个敌人
But he had an enemy.
州交通委员会
The State Transit Commission.
他们嘲笑他的计划，称之为“荒谬可笑”
They laughed at his plan and called it ridiculous.
他们要求特纳起草一份提案
They asked Turner to draft a proposal
以在郊区建设快速交通并缓解地铁的过度拥挤
to build rapid transit in the suburbs and relief subway overcrowding.
他们计划的核心是围绕曼哈顿下城和中城的两条环线
The core of their plan centered on two loop lines in Lower and Midtown Manhattan.
第一条环线设想了连接长岛铁路与曼哈顿下城和中城
The first loop envisioned connections between the Long Island Railroad in Lower and Midtown Manhattan.
第二条更大的环线旨在与新泽西的通勤线路建立连接
A second larger loop aimed to establish connections to New Jersey commuter lines.
市内的车站也将为本地乘客提供额外的快速交通服务
Stations within the city would also provide additional rapid transit service to local riders.
但海兰市长不是一个轻易退缩的人
But Mayor Highland wasn't one to back off.
市政府收回了交通监管权
The city took back control of transit oversight
并任命约翰·德莱尼为新成立的市交通局主席
and appointed John Delaney as chairman of the new city board of transportation.
到年底，他提出了独立的市有计划
By the end of the year, he put forth the independent city-owned plan.
他们将新建或延长一百英里的地铁线路
They would build or extend subway routes by a hundred miles.
曼哈顿十二英里
Twelve in Manhattan.
布朗克斯十九英里
Nineteen in the Bronx.
布鲁克林十七英里
Seventeen in Brooklyn.
以及皇后区五十二英里
And fifty-two in Queens.
它将通达除斯塔滕岛外的所有行政区
It would run to every borough except Staten Island.
但这其实无关紧要
But that didn't really matter.
他们的目标是为每个人的住所半英里内提供地铁服务
Their aim was to provide subway service within a half a mile of everyone's home.
这个宏伟的计划于1929年提出
The extravagant plan was proposed in 1929.
但股市崩盘后，完整的计划将永远无法实现
But after the stock market crash, the full plan would never be built.
大萧条期间，市政府的资金耗尽
During the Great Depression, the city's money ran out.
拉瓜迪亚市长将IRT和BRT合并为一个统一的市营系统以节省开支
Mayor LaGuardia united the IRT and BRT into a unified city-run system to save money.
尽管没有资金，市政府仍在为未来的扩建进行规划
Even though there were no funds, the city kept planning for future expansions.
1939年，德莱尼又公布了另一个计划
In 1939, Delaney unveiled another plan.
其中包括一条第二大道地铁，从曼哈顿下城延伸至布朗克斯
It included a second avenue subway, running from lower Manhattan into the Bronx.
在布朗克斯，将有三项主要的扩建工程
In the Bronx, there would be three main expansions.
而在皇后区，皇后大道和范威克大道线将被延长
And Queens, the Queens Boulevard, and Van Wyke Boulevard lines would be extended.
布鲁克林也将建立多条连接线路
Multiple connections would also be established in Brooklyn.
但这些计划也从未付诸实施
But these plans never moved forward either.
第二次世界大战转移了资源
World War II diverted resources.
一个新的角色也加入了战局
And so did a new player.
罗伯特·摩西在三十年代上台
Robert Moses came to power in the 1930s.
他庞大的高速公路项目被视为未来
His massive highway projects were seen as the future.
有轨电车、高架列车和地铁都已成为过去
Trollies, L trains, and subways were the past.
他主张拆除曼哈顿老旧的高架线路
He advocated for the demolition of old elevated lines in Manhattan.
它们最终都被拆除了
They were all demolished.
所有的有轨电车轨道都被拆除，为汽车让路
All the streetcar tracks were ripped out to make room for cars.
罗伯特·摩西在实现自己的愿景方面异常出色
Robert Moses was exceptionally good at achieving his own vision.
而交通部门的领导层则不然
Transit leadership was not.
直到1948年，他们都无法提高五美分的地铁票价
They were unable to raise the five-cent subway fare until 1948,
这意味着他们没有资金用于交通项目
which meant they had no funding for transit projects.
市政府1951年发行债券
When the city issued bonds in 1951,
将所得款项挪作他用，转而投入到旧有系统的养护和革新上
the revenue was diverted from new line construction to maintain and modernize the existing system.
与此同时，罗伯特·摩西将原定用于布朗克斯地铁扩建的资金
Meanwhile, Robert Moses diverted funds earmarked for a subway extension in the Bronx
挪用于建造他的贝尔公园大道项目
to build his Bell Parkway project.
他还抢占了为快速交通预留的路权，在布朗克斯修建了一条高速公路
And he snapped up rights-of-way reserve for rapid transit to build a highway in the Bronx.
在他长达五十年的统治结束时，市营地铁已严重资金不足
By the end of his 50-year reign, the city-operated subway was severely underfunded.
积压了大量的延迟维护，并且无法完成扩建计划
It had a backlog of deferred maintenance and was unable to complete plans for expansion.
地铁的控制权从市政府转移到了州政府
The subways were taken from city control and given to the state.
新成立的大都会运输署（MTA）推出了一个名为“行动计划”的宏伟提案
The new MTA launched an ambitious proposal called the Program for Action.
但就像大萧条和第二次世界大战曾让计划搁浅一样
But just like the Great Depression and World War II halted plans before,
七十年代的另一场经济危机也让这个计划戛然而止
another economic crash in the 1970s put a stop to this one too.
地铁被移交给了MTA，但它的状况持续恶化
The subway was transferred to the MTA, but it continued to decline.
在七十年代的城市财政危机期间，地铁变成了一个强有力的视觉隐喻
During the city's fiscal crisis in the 70s, the subways turned into a powerful visual metaphor.
到了九十年代，经济和地铁都开始复苏
By the 90s, the economy and the subway were recovering.
但数十年的资金不足已经造成了深远的影响
But decades of underfunding have taken their toll.
一百多年后，纽约市地铁仍未实现特纳和德莱尼的宏伟蓝图
More than a hundred years later, the New York City subway still has not achieved the grand designs of Turner and Delaney.
除非建造成本能够降低，否则它将永远无法实现
And unless it can get cheaper to build, it never will.
片尾广告时间，请观众有序离场